日本語字幕仕上げ：miraku  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
ハハハ おめでとう！
Congratulations!
君たちは レギュラー候補組だ
You guys will be the regular team members!
ちょ ちょっと監督！冗談でしょう？
Wait a minute manager...you're joking, right?
ボールも触らせずに ダッシュのタイムだけで…
They haven't handled the ball and you've already decided based on the results of the run?
Furthermore, why did you leave Murakoshi out?!
それに なぜ村越が外されるんだ？
納得できないだろうから
I figured that you all won't be able to accept it, so for now I'll have you to accept it.
これから納得してもらう
Fifteen minutes from now...
15分後に紅白戦だ
俺がこっちの指揮とるから
I'll take command of this group.
松ちゃん そっちね
Coach, you'll command the other group.
もし こっちに勝てたら
If you guys win, I'll reconsider my decision.
考え直すよ
それなら 文句ないだろ？
In this way, no one should have any complaints, right?
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
for the right
hold on tight
my story…
forever
You guys becoming the substitutes...
お前たちがサブだなんて
監督だって本気で言ってないさ
I'm sure the manager didn't mean it.
ただお前たちに発破を掛けるために
He's probably trying to rile you guys up.
手の込んだことをしただけだろ
なあ 村越
Right, Murakoshi?
真意は分かりませんが
I don't know he's thinking,
勝つだけです
But I only know that I have to win.
勝つぞ
We will win.
でも 監督 向こうは ほとんどレギュラーだし…
But manager, the other side comprises of regulars...
今のお前たちは 弱小クラブの控え
Currently, you guys are just a bunch of substitutes.
要するに 下の下の最低ライン ぎりぎりプロ
To put it short, you guys barely passed the pro level, a little better than the weaklings.
このままでいいのか？
Are you guys fine with that?
Imagine.
想像してみろよ
ここでレギュラー組を倒す
Defeating the regulars...
レギュラーの座を掴む
...and grabbing their spots.
Then, go on to win league games.
それでリーグ戦を勝ち進む
その時 お前たちの立場は変わる
Your life will never be the same again.
これは お前たちの
This is the first step towards your giant killing act!
ジャイアントキリングの始まりだぜ
But it's not going to be an easy task...
でも そんな簡単な事じゃ…
やる前からひるんで どうすんだ
Demoralised even before starting?
スコアは常に０対０から
Every match starts with a score of 0-0.
誰に対しても平等だ
This is fair towards everyone.
それに お前たちは勝てる
But you guys will win.
その武器を持ってる
You have the ability to do so.
おい 村越さんたちが ビブスつけてるぜ
Hey, Murakoshi and the rest are wearing yellow bibs.
Isn't that what the substitutes usually wear?
うちじゃ ビブスって いつもサブ組だろ？
But Tatsumi's sitting on the bench over there...
でも達海は 向こうのベンチにいるし…
達海…
Tatsumi...
どういう事だ 達海 コラ！
What's the meaning of this, Tatsumi?
Murakoshi shouldn't be a substitute, damn it!
村越さん サブ扱いしてんじゃねえぞ！
ディフェンスはマンマーク  俺には椿か
Defence style is man-marking.
And Tsubaki's onto me...
手加減はしねえ！
I will not go easy on you!
逆っ！
Reverse side!
Hey!
おいおい！ 張り切るのはいいけど
Going all out is good...
練習初日だぞ
But today is the first day of practice!
当たり考えろよ！
Put more thought into it!
I'm sorry.
す すいません
それでいい
No problem. Do the best that you can.
全力で当たってこい
はい！
Yes!
畏縮して 何もできないと思ったが
I thought he couldn't do anything right,
本気でぶつかってくるとはな
But he came at me at full force just now...
上等だ！
Fine. I accept the challenge.
受けて立ってやるよ
あ 奪った！
The ball's stolen!
速攻来るぞ！
He's coming!
しっかりゾーンで対応しろ！
Defend your zones properly!
Are we going to chase after that?
えっ 来ねえのか？
Never mind that, stop his passes!
いや いい
中盤でつぶせ！
逆サイドスペースが空いてる！
There's still a lot of open space!
二人！ フリーにさせるな！
Both of you don't need to run forcefully after him!
Once again, he's not passing it here!
また来ない？
まずい！
Oh crap!
越さん ナイス　チェイス！
Murakoshi, nice job!
なぜだ？
Why...
Why are they not taking their chances?
なぜ速攻のチャンスをみすみす見逃す？
このチーム編成は 明らかに さっきの 30ｍダッシュのタイムで 分けられている
That team's composition...
...was based on those who did well in the thirty-meter dashes.
向こうは スピードのある連中ばかり
They're a bunch of guys with fast legs.
ならば なぜ スピードで勝負をかけて来ない？
But why...
Why aren't they using their speed to get hold of this match?
Don't they have the guts?
度胸がねえのか？
いや違う
No, that's not it.
奴の指示だ
This must be...
...part of his plan.
変わんねえな
That arrogant attitude of his hasn't change.
上からものを見る態度
負けねえ
I won't lose.
俺は あんただけには 負けるわけにはいかないんだ！
You're the only person...
...that I cannot afford to lose to!
Defence line! Pull your defences together!
DFライン しっかり確認しとけ！  　　注：『DF』＝テイフエンス
あ～あ チャンスだったのに
That was such a good chance...
ハハハ　俺の言いつけ守って あいつら よくやってるよ
They're pretty good, following my orders closely.
本当に こんな戦術で勝てるの？
With this kind of strategy, can we really win?
ワンータッチプレー禁止だなんて
Forbidding one-touch play...
Is that really okay?
今のだって ワンータッチでつないでたら
If one-touch play is allowed,
１点取れてたかもよ
we might have scored a goal.
いいんだよ
It's fine.
目先の１点より大事なものがある
There's something more important than just scoring a goal.
それを示すのが先だ
Showing it to them comes before that.
その上で こっちが勝つ
And that will lead us to victory.
勝たなきゃならない
We have to win no matter what.
ETUのためにもな
For ETU's sake.
何だよ こいつら！
What's the matter with them?
どこまで消極的なんだよ
How cowardly can they be?
Thirty minutes have passed...and it's still goalless.
もうじき30分
１点も取れないとは…
それどころか すべてが 向こうのペースで 進められている気がする
Not only that, I feel like the game's already fallen to the pace of the other team.
おい！ あまり もっと しっかり！
Hey, put more effort into covering up!
Yes.
…ウッス
そういうことか
So that's how it is...
Listen carefully! From now on, stop trying to forcefully steal the ball away!
よく聞け！
これからは ボールをキープされても 無理に取りに行くな！
They are just trying to make us run!
向こうは俺たちを走らせたいだけだ
無駄に走るな
Don't simply waste your energy! Just keep to your defence zone and it'll be fine!
ゾーンでしっかり守れば問題ない！
あ～あ バレちゃった
Dang, he figured it out.
しかたねえな
Guess I've got no choice.
ワンータッチプレー解禁！
One-touch play ban is lifted!
仕掛けろ お前ら！
Go all out, you guys!
あっ 速攻のチャンス！
Here comes a chance!
ナイスクリア 村越！
Nice clearance, Murakoshi!
バカ野郎！ 簡単にぽんぽん回させんじゃねえ！
You idiot! Don't just dally around!
Look at the ball closely!
ボールウオッチャーになってるぞ！
すみません…
I'm sorry.
うわ～ 行き成りパスが綺麗に回った
They pulled out such a beautiful pass out of a sudden...how?
何で？
You're asking how? Well, that's because they're gathered together!
何でも何も そういう奴らを揃えたからだよ
え？ 先のダッシュのテストって 足の速い人たちでしょう？
You mean those guys who can run fast in the dashing exercise just now?
足の速いにも いろいろあんだろ
There are many types of fast runners too!
俺が重視したのは 疲れた時でも 速く走れるか… だよ
What I wanted was those who can still run fast even when exhausted.
45分走らせた ダッシュのタイムで 俺が見たのは
What I was looking at in the forty-five minutes dashing exercise was...
最初の１本とラストの１本
...the first and last minute.
正確に言うと その２本のタイム差だ
To put it more clearly, the time difference between these two minutes.
そのタイムの差が少ない奴 それはスタミナがある奴
The smaller the difference, the more stamina the person has.
その上タイムが速い奴
The faster the time, the more stamina and speed that the person has.
それはスピードがあって スタミナがある奴
そいつらがこっちのチーム　達海組だ
And those are the guys in my team.
Tatsumi's team.
逆に向こうは
On the other hand, the opposing side are made to dash for the ball in a game of keep-away, wasting their energy.
何本もダッシュした後
試合でも　ボールキープされて
走らされて バッティバッティ
それがワンータッチプレー禁止の狙い
That was the purpose of forbidding one-touch play?
そう
Correct. With the guys on the other team tiring out, even our lousy passes will get through.
向こうがヘロヘロになってくれりゃ
こっちが下手でもパスは通る
さあ どうする？
So, what will do now, Mr ETU?
Mr.ETU
おい！人任せにするんじゃねえ！
Hey! Don't play into their tricks!
Look at it properly!
集中しろ！
俺たちETUは堅守が武器だろ！
We're ETU's main weapons!
はっ… そいつは武器とは言わねえよ 村越
You don't call that a weapon, Murakoshi.
守って守って カウンター
Just defending all the way and doing counter attacks...
走れねえから それしかできねぇ
You’re saying that because you can no longer run.
ETUのサッカーはね…
ETU's soccer is...
Hmm...
何か面白くないんだよね
It's just not interesting, somehow.
シュートも少ないし
The shots on goal are few.
ハラハラするけど ワクワクしない
It does have tense moments, but it doesn't make you leap in joy.
うん そんな感じ
Yes, that's the feeling!
ガキんちょどもに 弱点をうまい事 言い当てられてる
Even the kids can already point out your weaknesses.
それが お前らの現実だ
This is an undeniable truth.
Don't screw with me.
ふざけんじゃねえ
これ以上 好きにやらせるか！
As if I'm going to let things go your way.
I have the technique and the experience.
経験と技術じゃ こっちが上だ
そして何より
And more than that, I have the pride of getting ETU to the way it is now!
俺たちには ETUを支えてきた意地と誇りがある！
前を向け！俺が仲間に闘志を見せる！
Look forward! I'll show my comrades that I'll get through them!
As the captain...
キャプテンの俺が！
足が前に出ねえ
My legs are giving away...
ふざけんじゃねえ
Damn it!
俺は… 俺はまだ…
I...
I still can...
止めろ 止めろ！
Stop him!
Murata!
ウラだ～！
Keeper!
キーパー！
Shoot it.
振り抜け！
Yes!!!
やった～！
Nice shot!
ナイッシュ！
よく決めた 世良！
You struck it well just now!
スゲー！
Awesome!
すっご～い！
Amazing!
本当に決めた！
It really ended just like you said it would!
哈哈
こっからは もう一方的さ
It'll be a one-sided match from here onwards.
I wonder who the weapon is now...
これが武器ってもんだ 村越
Murakoshi?
Or Tsubaki?
にしても 椿か…
おい
Hey! Did you see that, Shige?
見たかよ シゲちゃん
達海の奴　本当に監督やってるよ
Tatsumi...
...is really doing his job!
本当に帰ってきたんだ ETUの星が
He's really back.
ETU's ray of hope!
It's been a long time since I felt like really cheering them on!
何か久しぶりにワーッと応援してえよ
俺もだよ
Same here!
旗とかまだ押し入れにあるぜ
I still have their flag in my closet!
俺は太っちまったから ユニフォーム入らねえや
I've plumped up quite a bit so I can't wear their jersey!
やった やった～！
本当にやれちまったよ　俺たち！
We really won!
信じらんねえ！
Unbelievable!
俺なんか ２ゴール！
I actually scored two goals!
Hey, tone it down!
おい  よせって
Murakoshi...
村越…
イースト　トーキョー　ユナイテッド ？
East Tokyo United?
Why do you want to go to a team like that?
なぜあんな下位のチームに行く？
Murakoshi, you could have aimed for better teams instead...
村越君 君ならもっと上の…
あそこなら すぐに試合に出られます　それに…
I can be a regular immediately if I go there.
Also...
これから　ETUは強くなる
ETU will get stronger from now onwards.
あの人と俺 力を合わせれば…
If we combined our strength, it's no longer just a dream to be a big club.
ピーククラブになるのも夢じゃない
ゴール
It's the rookie, Murakoshi!
決めたのは ルーキー村越！
よっしゃ～！
Yeah! We might be able to clinch the cup again!
これでまた優勝を狙える
Good job, Murakoshi!
よくやった村越！
今夜うちの店へ来いよ～！
Next time, come to my shop!
弁当 ただでやるぞ！
I'll let you eat for free!
村越 よせ
Murakoshi, don't go! Their food is bad!
ここはまずいから
What did you say?!
なんだと  手前！
Come to our Chinese restaurant instead!
うちの中華 食いに来い！
餃子サービスするからよ
I'll treat you to pan-fried dumplings!
あの頃のように強くなる…
I've always believed in becoming stronger...
そう信じてやってきた
...just like that time.
Can you give us your autograph please?
あ あの サイン下さい
But...why?!
なのに なぜ…
ETU Club House Media Conference
質問いいですか？
Can I ask a question?
どうぞ！ 張り切ってどうぞ！
Please! Please do ask!
昨日 就任早々 紅白戦を行いましたよね
Yesterday, you had your boys play in a match even though you're just appointed,
レギュラー対サブ組
between the regulars and the substitutes,
結果は サブ組の圧勝でした
which ended in a one-sided victory for the subs.
そのサブ組を率いたのは　監督ご自身
And you're the one who was in charge of the subs.
となると 狙いはETUの世代交代なのでしょうか？
Would that mean that you're planning to change the players?
う～ん… どうかなぁ…
I wonder about that.
はっきりしろよ はっきり
Say it out clearly!
では こちらが受けた印象も含めて　率直にお聞きします
Then, along with my impression of the situation, allow me to ask you directly.
Mr.ETU村越ですら 控えの可能性はあるのでしょうか？
Is there a possibility that even Mr ETU, Murakoshi...
...will be relegated to the reserves?
わかんないで～す
I don't know.
けどね
But...
これだけは決めたから はっきり言える
I can only tell you this.
村越って選手に関しては…
Regarding the player, Murakoshi...
こ…　越さん！
Koshi!
That guy, just now at the media conference-
あいつが今 記者会見で…
Damn, it's tiring!
いや～ ああ疲れた
でも よかったよな
But well, it's a big success!
大成功で
Tatsumi! Saying that out just now,
達海さん
突然あんな事言って…
didn't you even consider about Murakoshi's feelings?
もう少し 村越さんへの配慮とかないの？
That's a little too harsh on him!
あれじゃ いくら何でも かわいそ…
い　痛い…
ちょっと！
Wait!
こりゃ ちょうどいい
Just at the right time.
何なんですか あんたは
What do you plan to do?
急に戻って来て
Coming back suddenly...
いきなりチーム混乱させて
...and messing up the team big time!
その上 俺をキャプテンから外すだと
Above all, you're removing me as the captain?!
What do you know about ETU?
あんたにETUの何が分かる？
I fought alongside ETU for ten years!
俺は10年間 ETUで戦ってきた
The one who abandoned ETU...
ETUを見捨てて出てった あんたに何が分かるってんだよ！
What do you know about it?
The first impression's important.
第一印象って大事だぜ
見慣れてないから
I can see the team's weakness clearly precisely because I'm not familiar with it.
欠点だってよく見える
それで相手を負かせる時だってある
Sometimes, there's also a need to leave it to someone else to handle things.
俺の存在が チームの欠点だと言いたいのか？
Are you saying that my presence...
...is the reason for the team's weakness?
走れなくなった選手は　もういらねえか？
No need of players who can no longer run?
若手に徹底的にやられるような　キャプテンは…
A captain who was completely defeated by a bunch of greenhorns?
そんな事 あんたにだけは　言われたくねえよ！
That's the one thing I don't want to hear from you!
あんたが出て行った事で ETUは崩壊したんだ
ETU crumbled after you left!
２部に落ちて 主力が抜けても
Even when we're relegated and not sponsored, I stayed!
俺は残った
キャプテンとしての責任があったからな！
Because I felt it was my responsibility as the captain!
Pulling together a team from a bunch of depressed guys...
死に物狂いでチームを纏めた
We managed to get ourselves back to the first division after four years!
４年かけて１部に戻った
俺は あんたが 潰しかけたチームを
I had given my all in rebuilding the team that you destroyed!
必死になって立て直してきたんだ
A loss again!
また負けた！
How many years are we going to stay in the second division?
何年２部にいるつもりだよ！
Didn't it go downhill after Tatsumi left?
達海 抜けてから ぼろぼろじゃねえか！
本当だよな
They're right...
We've fallen that much...
ここまで減ったか
Manager!
監督
ジョルジニアは次の試合には？
When will Jorgino play again?
That guy returned back to Brazil already.
ああ あいつはブラジルへ帰ったよ
まったく とんでもねえ外国人つかませやがって
Damn it, using useless foreigners who can't even play...
あんなフロントで勝てるかよ
Can we even win with that front?
俺についてきてくれ
Come with me.
クラブの補強も期待できない
We can't count on help from others.
でも…
If we listen to what the higher-ups says, we won't be able to win.
上のやり方 聞いてたって
勝利は得られない
俺たち自身の力でつかみ取るんだ！
We are going to grab it with our own strength.
そのために
For that, I will...
俺は…
すべてを賭ける！
...bet everything I have!
チームの戦力 バランスを考え
The team's offensive power, balance; I've searched for whatever methods that we can use to win.
勝てる術を探した…
チームを第一に…
I've sacrificed everything to get this team to the top.
そのために　自らだって犠牲にしてきた
自分の事しか考えなかった　あんたに
Can you, who only think for yourself...
俺の気持ちが分かるか？！
...even understand my feelings?
キャプテンとして やるべき事はやってきた
I've done everything a captain has to do.
この10年間
For the past ten years, I've bet everything I had on ETU!
俺は 自分のすべてをETUに　賭けてきたんだ
だからキャプテン外すんだよ
That's why I'm relieving you of your captain duties.
チーム事情
The team's situation...
チームのバランス 戦術
The team's balance...
Offensive power...
そんな物まで お前が背負い込む必要はねえ
There is no need for you to worry about them.
俺に言わせりゃ
To put it short, you were just not blessed with a good coach.
お前はただ
いい監督に恵まれなかっただけだ
お前は紅白戦で負けた
You lost in the match just now.
若手に比べりゃ まるで走れねえ
You can't run as fast as the youngsters.
それでも勝てる自分の武器を
Even so, find the weapon that will enable you to win.
これからお前は死ぬ気で探せ
In exchange,
その代り
お前が　背負ってきたもんの半分は
The burden you have carried on your shoulders for all this while...
これから　俺が命懸けで 背負ってやるよ
...let me bear half of it, with my life on the line!
寒い
It's cold...
The other teams are all in the South training comfortably...
ほかのチームは南部の島とかで
ぽかぽか陽気の中キャンプしてるってえのに
ETU's camp ground: The Island Of Dreams Stadium
It can't be helped. We're a poor club afterall.
仕方ねえよ
うちは貧乏クラブなんだから
Cold! Are we really going to train here?
寒い！
本当にここでキャンプするんの？
自分が連れてきたんじゃないすか！
Isn't that your suggestion in the first place?
俺だって嫌だよ
Even I didn't want it! I'd rather go for somewhere in the South!
南部がいいに決まってんじゃん！
随分と　まあワイワイと
You're just all words, aren't you?
現役の時から
Seeing you from the time when you were playing actively as an ace,
チームの中心で楽しく　サッカーしてきた人は
監督になっても　楽しそうにやるもんだ
Aren't you basking in the limelight as a manager too?
Being fine even when seeing the guys below you suffering; you seem to be just such a person.
下の人間が苦しんでても関係ない
そんなふうに見えるわ
コラ 黒田！ いい加減にしろ！
Hey Kuroda! Cut it out!
全く…　すみません監督
I'm sorry, manager.
別にいいのに
I am not really bothered about it.
あの２人
Those two...
黒田と杉江は
Kuroda and Sugie...how should I say it?
何というか
どんな時も 村越に付いてきたような連中なもんで
They are Murakoshi's loyal followers.
恐らく　村越がキャプテンを外された事で…
It's probably because you stripped Murakoshi of his captaincy.
やっぱり　最初の課題は先ずそこだな
As I thought, that's going to be the issue that has to be ironed out first.
え～ では
And now,
本年度 ETUギャンプ初日のメニューを発表します
I'll announce the content for the first day of the yearly ETU training camp.
自習～
Self-practice!
Umm...
え～… あのう… はい？
What?
Self-practice! Don't you know about it?
自習だってば 松ちゃん　知らないの？
Self-practice!
自習
No, that's not what I meant...
いや そういう事じゃなくて…
Like I said, think about what you need to do on your own.
だから 自分らで考えて行動すんだよ
監督やコーチに　言われた事やるんじゃなくて
You don't just listen to what the manager says.
自分から自主的に動けってこと　プロなんだし
But have initiative to do what you need to do, that's how a pro does it.
じゃあ 俺は寒いので 温まってきま～す
And so, since it's so cold, I'll go warm myself up a little.
ほ～ら コーチも行くよ
Come on, put some effort in it now!
あっと …それから村越
By the way Murakoshi,
お前は もうキャプテンじゃねえかんな
You're no longer the captain...
お前は口出し禁止
...so don't go around ordering people, okay?
分かった？
You've got find the way to believe
carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say "never look back"
追い風を待って
そうchanceをのがすなら
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
no tears,Yes Let it go！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough！(We'll go！)
限界追い越せ
行け キツイほど
heart in red
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Go on！(We'll go！)
あすは見えない だから
It's time to go
やめられない
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough！(We'll go！)
共に乗り越えて 行け
見えるか It's daybreak there
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
予測できないだから
It's time to go
止められない
Where did that idiot of a manager go?
何処へいた　あの馬鹿監督！
To hell with self-practice!
何か　自習だ！
Do you think you can win?
勝てるんですか　それで
This looks bad, manager!
ヤバイですよ　監督
もっと面白くしようと思って
I was just thinking of making it a little more interesting.
ルイジ吉田　愛称はジーノ
Luigi Yoshida.
People call me Gino.